Bala Subrahmanyam Varanasi

Email: <u>vabasu@gmail.com</u> Mobile: +919819633692

Summary

A Senior Software Engineer with more than five years of professional experience from design and document to implementation of various Web and Mobile applications using Python/Django, Ruby on Rails and Android in a fast-paced deadline oriented environments.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Glitterbug Technology, November 2015 - Present

- Build scalable software through architecture discussions with the leadership
- Participate with other teams, to provide solutions for our customers
- Manage Sprint/Development cycle for the development team and manage team during the cycle
- Determine complexity level of a story in a Sprint/Development cycle
- Communicate with leadership on current project status
- Error prevention and error detection possible
- Continuous integration
- Test-driven development
- Roundup or Track for bug tracking and project management

Software Engineer at TinyOwl Technology, April 2015 – November 2015

Responsible for developing and maintaining micro service applications using Ruby On Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, AWS and etc...

Founder at Firebolt Labs, Aug 2014 – April 2015

Headed the day-to-day-operations, as well as handled the company's product and consulting projects.

Software Developer at Crypsis Technologies, Sept 2013 - July 2014

Responsible for the development of web and mobile apps using various technologies like Ruby on Rails, Android and NodeJS.

Intern and Software Developer at Agiliq Info Solutions, Dec 2011 – Aug 2013

Worked with several clients across the globe on various projects and helped them in building various web and mobile apps using Python/Django and Android.

Interests

FOSS, Web Development, Mobile Development and DevOps.

Skills

Data Structures, Algorithms, Databases, Python, Django, Ruby on Rails, Ansible, GIT.

Projects

Django Applications

- <u>CoverFox Insurance</u>, an online insurance destination.
- <u>Sufo</u>, an Educational Video site for Physicians.
- Feature Developments in Suggestar.
- Customized the Django Admin CMS for <u>CineSport</u>, an innovative web video syndication company.
- Feature Development in <u>TravelDojo</u>, a company to create travel guides to the Southeast Asia region.

- Testing and Bugfixes Ocassio Health Strategies.
- Seeded HyderabadWiki with Wikipedia dump in LocalWiki Format.
- The Xaming Arena, a simple Online Examination system using Django framework.

Ruby on Rails Applications

- TinyOwl, a food ordering application.
- Mr Delicious, an online food delivery system.
- <u>Investment Club</u> by <u>StockViews</u>.
- Feature Development in <u>Swym</u>.
- <u>Virtual Analyst</u> by <u>Analytics Intelligence</u>.
- Feature Developments and Test Cases Development in Mega Golf Virtual League.

Android Applications

- "Windows Ambassador", an application by Microsoft.
- "Where's My App?", checks the availability status of apps and games in the Windows Phone Store.
- "Baby Names", a simple android app to choose a baby name.

Open Source

- Feature Development in django-graphos.
- Bugfixes and pep8 improvements in scikit-learn.
- pep8 improvements in joblib.
- <u>Sentiment Analyzer</u>, a simple sentiment classification tool for Telugu Language.
- Feature Improvements and Test Cases in Join.agiliq.com
- Improvments to code samples in DjenOfDjango.

Publications

"Python Requests Essentials", a book which showcases fundamental as well as advanced Python Requests concepts. (ISBN-10: 1784395412) (ISBN-13: 978-1784395414)

Education

- Artificial Intelligence Nanodegree, Udacity, January 2017 Present.
- **Batchelor of Technology**, Information Technology from Vishnu Institute of Technology, 2008 2012.
- **Intermediate Education** from Santhiniketan Junior College, 2006 2008.
- SSC from G.V&K.B.M School, 2006.

As a Speaker

PyCon India, 2013; SciPy 2011 & 2013 and CoDec 2012.